ANDRE GODOY

Senior Full Stack Software Engineer

ABOUT

Adaptable Senior Full Stack Developer specializing in frontend development, backed by comprehensive knowledge of backend technologies. Proficient in React and TypeScript, with a keen eye for crafting compelling user experiences. Collaborated closely with product teams to prioritize and deliver feature-rich interfaces and services. With special interest in interactive applications, I love learning new ways and technologies to communicate with the end user.

SKILLS

JavaScript, Git: 10+ years
TypeScript, React, Redux, Webpack, SQL: 6 years
Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, REST APIs: 5+ years
NodeJS, Express, GraphQL: 2 years
NextJS, Express: 1 year
Apollo GraphQL, Terraform: <1 year

CONTACT

+55 19 99258-3789 andregodoy0@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/agodoy in

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Revelo, Dec 2023 - Mar, 2024

NextJS, TypeScript, tRPC, Prisma, PostgreSQL, TailwindCSS, OpenAl API

Temporary contract to establish a robust full stack foundation for a search and comparison engine, integrated with Artificial Intelligence to assist users. The work involved the selection of tools and frameworks, as well as the setup of the database, API and design architecture.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

NextRoll, Jun 2018 - Jul 2023

TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, React, Redux, Postgres, REST APIs, AWS, Golang, GraphQL

Designed and shape the architecture of an evolving product by working closely with product managers and designers to develop customer-focused features: user interfaces, dashboards, and the services that power them.

- Mentored junior engineers on the team
- Learned Golang to build upon an existing GraphQL endpoint, leveraging Apollo framework
- Analyzed requirements to architect and implement data sharing integrations with partners using existing infrastructure
- Started an ongoing refactor of a dual purpose web server to SPA microservice, making use of AWS CloudFront Functions to remove the backend while avoiding service disruption
- Implemented and maintained RESTful endpoints in Python

SOFTWARE ANALYST

Instituto de Pesquisas Eldorado, Aug 2015 - May 2018

JavaScript, AngularJS, Gulp, Java, GCP

- Contributed to the backend of an application that communicates with mobile devices in large scale. Also acted on the development of the frontend, developing and bringing tools that made development easier and faster
- Continued the development of an AngularJS App to replace the UI of an automated test execution environment in Java, recreating several functionalities from the previous tool. Also implemented a few REST web services

ANALYST DEVELOPER

Squadra Tecnologia, Apr 2014 - Aug 2015

Android, JavaScript, NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL, REST APIs

- Contributed to an educational prototype for Android tablets with augmented reality, teacher-customizable class material, and real-time feedback
- Participated on a project to create a cloud for doctors and clinic managers and an Android App for the patients, integrated with Social Networks

PROGRAMMER

D-Wings, Jan 2013 - Feb 2014

iOS, Android, JavaScript, SQL, PHP, jQuery

Building apps for iOS, Android and Web using HTML5 technologies.

- Ported an Web App to iOS and Android without additional frameworks

DEVELOPER

Tectoy Digital, Oct 2010 - Dec 2012

Java, PHP, Android

As an intern, ported J2ME games and added internationalization. Then worked on a Facebook Flash game, experimented with backend web development and Android app customization

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF SÃO PAULO

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science, 2007 - 2011

- Undergraduate Research: "Game-Scrum: An Approach to Agile Game Development"
- Fellowship of the Game: student group formed to study and practice game development